- You sure it's the Russians? - 100%, sir.
肯定是俄国人？　　百分百肯定
Submarine launched 12 to 15 megatons. They went to strike status.
潜艇有近15兆吨核武，准备出击
The Roosevelt's splashed six incoming cruise missiles.
罗斯福号击落六枚巡航导弹
The Russians are moving west. Our Berlin brigade are outnumbered.
俄军西移，我们在柏林势孤力弱
Sir, we've got a launch from Alyesk, Central Russia.
俄罗斯中部的艾耶斯克亦有威胁
What the hell is in Alyesk?
什么威胁？
SS-18 ICBMs. Probable targets: New York, Washington, here.
SS-18洲际弹道导弹
- How good is this ceiling? - Anything but a direct hit.
天花板坚固吗？　　抵御不了直击
Satellites confirm birds in the air, first impact estimated 25 minutes.
卫星证实有战机，25分钟内施袭
- Is that accurate? - It's accurate.
资料准确吗？　　准确
- I advise we go to DEFCON-1. - Get President Zorkin on the hotline.
一级紧急状态吧　　　联络索总统
Zorkin is missing. We have reports of a coup in Moscow.
他不见了，接报莫斯科发生政变
General Bulgakov is calling the shots now.
现在由鲍上将掌权
Who the hell is Bulgakov?
他究竟是谁？
The asshole who wanted to use nukes in Chechnya.
那个想在车臣用核弹的混蛋
Sir, DEFCON-1. We're out of time.
进入一级紧急状态，时间无多
Do it.
动手吧
Mr President.
总统先生
It'll take a minute for the launch to process after you give the order.
系统在你下令后，一分钟才启动
Before the order can be taken, an ID check must be performed.
下令前，要先核对身分
My ID number is fifth from the top.
数下来第五个号码就是
- Sir, it's your wife on 2104. - Thank you.
总统，夫人在2104线　　　谢谢
- Yeah. - The order must be confirmed
请说　　　要有名单上的人士…
- by someone on the approved list. - Shit.
下令才能动手　　　可恶
Gene Revell, National Security Advisor.
国家安全顾问韦真
Is it black tie? OK. I'm on my way.
要穿礼服？好，我马上来
Can we...
我们可否…
...finish this up some other time?
改天才继续演习？
No.
不可以
We've got to update these fire drills, Billy.
我们得更新这些演习程序
If the shit ever hits the fan, I'm not going underground.
若有麻烦，我才不要躲到地底去
It's a goddamn tomb down there.
地底藏有一个核弹
We have to choose someone else to face off against besides the Russians.
还要找人对付俄军以外的坏蛋
Really? Let's see. Who else has 27,000 nukes for us to worry about?
是吗？还有谁有27000枚核弹？
It's the guy with one I'm worried about.
我是担心那个有一枚核弹的家伙
I have to send some folks to Russia,
我要派人去俄罗斯监察
inspect their nuclear decommissioning facility at Armazas.
他们在阿马沙斯解除核武的工作
- Arzamas. - Yeah, whatever.
是阿尔扎马斯　　　什么也好
- Someone from your staff should go. - I'll go.
派你的手下去　　　我亲自去
- Billy, send staff. - I want to go.
比尔，派人去　　　我想亲自去
OK.
好吧
Don't underestimate Zorkin. Between his economy, crime, Chechnya...
别低估老索
- His liver. - What's left of it. How is he?
他的肝　　　所剩无几，他怎么样？
He's scheduled a press conference for today, so we know he can sit up.
今天有记者会，他应该能坐起来
Chechnya is part of Russia.
车臣是俄罗斯的一部分
Only criminals and their friends in the West who wish it to be separate.
只有罪犯和其西方朋友想它分裂
Mr President, if you will kindly come back...
总统先生，请你回去…
Do you guys see what I see?
你们有留意到吗？
- His jacket? - He used to be able to button it up.
他的西装吗？　　本来还能扣钮扣
He's getting fat.
他发福了
I know how he feels. Oh, wow. Look at that.
我明白那种感受…看这个
Maybe it's not the same jacket.
也许是另一件
Yeah, it has shiny sleeves. He wore it the last time he got out of the hospital.
看衣袖，他上次出院时也穿这个
- He's off the diet. - And off the wagon. He slurred...
他没节食　　　还开酒戒喝个大醉
That must be why Cherlinski is there, to keep him off the sauce.
所以老卓在旁，以免他喝个不停
Where's Cherlinski?
老卓在哪里？
Next to... What's her name? The chick with the brown hair.
在…她叫什么？那个棕发的女人
- Elena Rishkov. - That is not Cherlinski.
雷莲娜　　　那不是老卓
Bzz! Busted. It's Cherlinski.
错了，那是老卓
You're thinking Cherpitski. It ain't him.
你说的是老查，不是他
- I know. It's Cherlinski. - No, it's not. Trust me.
那是老卓　　　不，相信我好了
He's next to Elena Rishkov. He was banging her at the Geneva summit.
他在莲娜旁边，还在日内瓦胡混
Cherlinski was not at Geneva. Cherpitski was.
老卓没去日内瓦，那是老查
Cherpitski was banging Elena Rishkov?
老查跟雷莲娜有染？
I just said Zorkin's putting on weight. Why reduce it to sex? It's disgusting.
我只是说老索胖了
I agree. Write it up. If he is putting on weight,
我同意，记下这个…若他胖了
that might have health consequences, so get it in the afternoon brief.
定会影响健康，下午简报写这个
Oh, and somebody find out who is banging Elena Rishkov. This is good.
找人查是谁搭上莲娜，这有看头
What shall we make of Chechnya asking the West for protection?
车臣要求西方庇护是怎么回事？
She is like a beautiful virgin, escaping the clutches of a lecherous bear,
这就如漂亮处女想摆脱好色老头
and running to Bill Clinton to save her maidenhood.
跑去找克林顿帮忙保贞操
A poet once wrote, "Meet the new boss, same as the old boss."
俗语有云「天下乌鸦一样黑」
He could have been writing of us, of Europe in the 21 st century.
这也许适合套用在21世纪的欧洲
Over 50 years of America and Russia
五十多年来，美、俄一直…
imposing their will on the European community,
将其意愿强加在欧洲社会上
East and West,
东、西双方
and we're still treated like children...
都还当我们是小孩
...but without the toys or the goodnight chocolates.
但却没给我们玩具和糖果
Each day we lose a little bit more
每一天我们都在失去更多…
of our separate sovereign ability to determine our own futures
独立自主，决定未来路向的能力
and each day the world comes just a little bit closer to that terrible moment
而每一天，这世界亦更接近小蝴蝶…
when the beating of a butterfly's wings unleashes a hurricane...
拍动翅膀、掀起大风波的可怕时刻
...God himself cannot stop.
这个连老天也阻止不了
So what is it?
这究竟是什么？
Are you blind?
你看不见吗？
It's a bomb.
是个炸弹
Where's the fuse?
那么雷管呢？
It's warm.
还是热的
So am I. Come on. I don't have all night.
我也是，赶快，时候不早了
It's a dud.
这是个哑弹
Let's get it on the truck.
快搬它上车
But how can we sell it now?
但怎么把它卖掉？
There's always someone who'll buy this crap.
总会有人买这种垃圾
I cannot stand all these questions about my health.
我最讨厌这些健康问题
I am to be described as "robust" and "healthy".
该形容我「精神爽利又健康」
Is that yours or mine?
是你的还是我的？
It must be yours. Mine's just for show.
一定是你的，我那个好看不中用
It's not the hospital.
不是医院传呼我
- Hi. - You're still here.
你好　　　你还在这里
Well, I think to be accurate, it's actually you who's still here.
准确点说，应该是你还在这里
Oh, right.
没错
Not that I'm complaining.
我不是在抱怨
Jack...
杰克…
I know this is new and all, but...
我知道我们初相识，但是…
...I have something I have to say or I'm going to explode.
我有话要说，实在忍不住了
I don't want you to be scared.
我也不想吓怕你
What?
什么事？
You're in love with me.
你爱上了我
Jack, I'm a medical professional. I can read the symptoms.
我是医生，懂看病症的
You're definitely in love with me.
你确实爱上了我
And that scares you?
这个令你害怕？
Not even a little.
一点都没有
But I think it scares you.
但你却害怕
No, not even a little.
一点都不怕
And for the record, you're the one who brought it up.
话说回来，是你先提起这个
Forget it.
别管它
- I'm gonna get it. - No way. It'll stop.
我要接传呼　　　不，任由它响吧
I don't know who this is.
我不知道是谁传呼我
- Just go about your business. - The timing sucks.
你谈你的公事　　　真扫兴
Do what you have to do. I understand.
你做你该做的，我会体谅
Yes, this is Dr Muller.
对，我是梅医生
Muller. You paged me.
但你传呼我
Hello.
喂
Stop! Yes, this is Jack Ryan.
别闹了！我是杰克・雷恩
Jesus.
老天！
OK. I'll be there in half an hour.
好的，我在半小时内赶到
I gotta go. I have an emergency at work.
我要走了，工作上有急事
I have to go. I'm sorry.
我要走了，对不起
Cathy, how about dinner tonight?
卡丝，今晚一起吃饭好吗？
Yeah.
好的
- How about tomorrow night? - Jack, I said yes to tonight.
明晚呢？　　别得寸进尺
I know.
我知道
What kind of emergency does a historian have?
历史学家会有什么急事？
He died at 0420 Zulu. 81/2 hours later, they swore in a new president.
他在上午4时20分逝世
- Who is he? - Alexander Nemerov.
他是谁？　　尼艾历
You're kidding. I wrote a paper about him a year ago.
别说笑，一年前我以他大作文章
- I said he could be the next guy. - I know.
说他会当总统　　　我知道
- Nobody read it. - They're reading it now.
没人看过那篇文章　　　现在有了
- Who? - Cabot.
谁？　　老卡
I've been here 14 months. He doesn't know what I look...
我来了14个月，他从未见过我…
- Are you Ryan? - Yes, sir.
你就是杰克・雷恩？　　是的，局长
What is this? "The Paper Chase"?
怎么回事？是便服日吗？
- Sir, my... - Come on, we're late.
局长…　　快来，我们迟到了
You're about to breathe air that's way over your pay grade, so listen.
你这是越级挑战，所以要听好
You'll be asked for advice. Be sure you know what you're talking about.
我会问你意见，记得要小心说话
Don't be afraid to say you don't know.
不懂的就直说无妨
Choose your words carefully. They could become policy.
小心措词，那可能会成为政策
Hey, you. Give me your coat.
你脱下西装褛
Come on, you'll get it back.
赶快，稍后还给你
Tie.
领带
So, intelligence committee?
是情报委员会？
I've watched these on C-SPAN. Never actually been to one.
我在电视上看过，但没参加过
You've never watched one of these on C-SPAN.
你从未在电视上看过这场面
Our most important assessment comes from a source inside the Kremlin.
最重要的线报源自克里姆林宫
In his opinion, Nemerov does not owe his ascension to the military.
线人认为俄军不太听老尼指挥
Everyone has opinions, Mr Cabot.
人人都各有想法
I respect that.
我尊重这一点
This morning, my wife woke up and said I was old, bald and ugly.
今早我太太说我又老又丑
Is that a question, Mr Chairman?
那是提问吗？主席
I told her appearances aren't everything.
我跟她说外表不是一切
- Would you agree? - I certainly would.
你同意吗？　　当然同意
Now, this new fellow, Nezmeroz. Is that his name?
新总统叫莱艾历吗？
Nemerov, sir.
是尼艾历
Despite what your source says, we hear that Nezmeroz is a hardliner.
虽是线报，但据说他是个强硬派
Is he a hardliner?
真有此事吗？
No.
不
It's too soon to make that assessment.
这个言之尚早了
According to CNN,
据CNN报导
your Mr Nezmeroz is making promises to rebuild the Russian empire.
尼总统承诺重建俄罗斯帝国
That sounds pretty rash from where I sit.
对我而言，他口气太大了
If I were sitting in Chechnya, I'd be even more worried.
若我在车臣，那我还会更担心
Sir, Nemerov only said that to get the hardliners off his back.
老尼只是说，他会清除强硬派
If we leave him alone, Russia will stabilise.
若我们不烦他，俄罗斯会更稳定
When I asked for your advice, I didn't mean that you should actually speak.
我问你意见，并不代表你可以开腔
Mr Cabot?
卡局长？
Some of our assets in the Russian government who know Mr Nemerov
在俄国政府，了解老尼的线人
have not had a chance to report in.
还没有机会更新情报
I'd like to take a couple of days and gather more information for you
看来花多两天时间，搜集更多资料
before characterising him,
才下定论比较好
but I do maintain my opinion that appearances can be deceiving.
但我仍然相信，外表是可以骗人的
You're saying I'm wrong?
那你是说我错了？
Absolutely, Mr Chairman.
当然了，主席
I don't think you're ugly.
我不觉得你样子很丑
- I was out of line. I apologise. - Senators don't like to be surprised.
刚才真失礼　　　参议员不爱惊喜
I hint at what I'm gonna tell them, then I give them a while to get used to it.
我会作暗示、表态，让他们适应
Then I tell them.
然后才告之真相
- I understand. - Good.
我明白　　　好极了
But I'm right about Nemerov.
但老尼的事我说对了
Your girlfriend like this stubborn streak in you?
你女朋友喜欢你这么固执？
What?
什么？
Cathy Muller, second year surgical resident,
梅卡丝，第二年住院实习医生
Baltimore Memorial Hospital.
巴尔的摩纪念医院
Welcome to the CIA, sport.
欢迎你加入中情局
Your intelligence is a little flawed. I wouldn't call her my girlfriend... yet.
你的情报不够准，她不算是女友
- What exactly would you call her? - Great. Amazing.
那该是什么？　　棒极了的女孩
She's just afraid to commit.
她就是害怕承诺
He's terrified of commitment.
他对承诺害怕极了
A man who's afraid of commitment after three dates? Alert the media.
约会三次就讲承诺？真是大新闻
- I know, I know. - So what does he do?
我知道　　　他做哪一行？
He was in the marines before he hurt his back.
他当过海军陆战队，因背伤退役
- Now he's a historian. - Yawn.
现在是历史学家　　　闷蛋
No. He works for a think tank across the river.
不，他替一个智囊团做事
Double yawn.
大闷蛋
All right, Rita. Let's see what you have to say after we meet him tonight.
丽达，等你今晚见过他再说
He's...
他…
...cute?
英俊吗？
- I have fat fingers. - Cathy! Cute scale, one to ten.
手指很粗　　　卡丝，他有多帅？
Oh, God. I don't know.
我不知道
Twelve.
超英俊
Ask them where they found this.
问他们从哪儿找到这个
In the field, in the Golan.
在哥兰高地
There was a lot of fighting there in 1973. Did they witness it?
73年那儿常打仗，他们在场吗？
This one says he lost his son.
这老头说他儿子死掉了
Does he remember, was there a plane shot down?
他记得有飞机被击落吗？
Yes, an Israeli jet, destroyed.
有，以色列战机被毁
This is worthless.
这个不值钱
But tell him I will give him $400... because of his son.
但我会给他四百元…为了他儿子
Thank... thank you.
多…多谢
Thank you.
多谢
It's not the sort of thing you find lying around normally.
（叙利亚，大马士革）
I found her in the attic of an old mansion house in Glasgow.
在格拉斯哥古老大宅的阁楼
Your little trip to the attic has got you a piece worth now about L1,000,
你这次找到值一千镑的宝物
even in this condition, and had she been in better condition, even more.
要是它比较完好，那会更值钱
A jolly nice find.
好一个发现
In fact, what I thought I'd found was a garden ornament.
其实我以为找到一件花园摆设
Hello, Cathy?
是卡丝吗？
Hi. I'm glad you called. I'm running late. Can you come a half an hour later?
幸好你来电，我赶不及了
I can't make it. I'm really sorry.
我不能赴约，对不起
- It's a last-minute work thing. - What's that noise?
临时有急事　　　什么声音？
I'm calling from a plane.
我在飞机上打电话给你
- This just came up. I tried to call you. - Where are you going?
我试过找你的　　　你要去哪里？
- I can't tell you that. - Jack.
不便相告　　　杰克
You can't tell me?
你不便相告？
Jack.
杰克
- Hold on. Yes, sir? - What are you doing?
慢着…怎样？　　你在做什么？
I had a date tonight, so I had to cancel.
我要取消今晚的约会
Don't be stupid. Tell her where you're going. Tell her who you work for.
傻瓜，告诉她你为谁出差好了
She'll be impressed.
她会另眼相看
OK. I work for the CIA.
好吧，我是替中情局做事的
The director asked me to go with him to Russia to do a nuclear arms inspection.
局长要我陪他去俄国检查核武
- Hello? - That is so lame.
喂？　　这借口真烂
I swear, we get to inspect to make sure they're decommissioning their arsenal.
我们真的去看他们有否解除核武
Hello?
喂？
Thanks. Thanks a lot.
真是感激不浅
Zdravstvuyte, William Cabot.
你好，比尔・卡伯特
President Nemerov.
尼总统
Pleasure, sir.
幸会，总统先生
May I present Mrs Lathrop.
这是赖太太
Mr President.
总统先生
- General Rand. - Mr President.
伦上将　　　总统先生
- Dr Ryan.
雷博士　　　总统先生
You must be the Dr Ryan who's done such interesting research on me.
就是你以我为题材…作有趣的研究
You should not be surprised. We know quite a bit.
你不该感到意外，我们消息灵通
We know how wrong your report was that I had many girlfriends in college.
说我在大学有很多女友…大错特错
I met my wife in my third year and have not looked at another woman since.
第三年认识我太太，自此用情专一
I was referring to the first two years... sir.
我是指大学头两年…总统
Where you received highest honors in English.
当时你修读英文，成绩优异
I like you.
我喜欢你
Well, in that case, so do I.
那么我也一样
I apologise for interjecting myself in your inspection tour,
抱歉，打扰你进行检查的工作
but I have a message for President Fowler.
但我有个口信给霍总统
You could just call him on the phone.
你大可以给他电话
I would like him to hear it from you, his friend of many years,
我想由他的老朋友转告口信
who received it personally from me,
我要亲自见你
and saw my expression and the language of my body as I spoke it.
让你看到我的表情和身体语言
I understand.
我明白的
Chechnya is an internal affair.
车臣是我国的内政
What we do there should be none of your concern.
我们的做法与你们无关
I will relay the message, but I don't think he will agree.
我会传这口信，但他该不会同意
Some people in my country will use this issue to weaken me.
本国有人想借此来削减我的势力
Some people in my country say
我国却有人说
your war in Chechnya is exactly your weakness.
车臣之战正是你的弱点所在
Chechnya is a nation of criminals.
车臣全国满是罪犯、坏蛋
Every day brings another cowardly attack on innocent Russian citizens.
每天都作懦夫所为，伤害百姓
It is none of your concern.
这问题不用贵国担心
Stability is our concern.
我们担心政局的稳定性
Peace in Chechnya is our concern.
我们担心车臣是否太平
And, if I may speak frankly...
还容我直说…
...your control over your military concerns us too.
我们也担心你对俄军的控制力
For you to get involved here, it's... like sleeping with another man's wife.
你来这儿…就如搞人家的老婆
And what you are suggesting is that afterward
而你所建议的是事后…
they can all live together under the same roof.
他们能相安无事，和平共处
But what really happens is the betrayed husband buys a gun.
但关键是戴了绿帽的丈夫买了枪
- That went well. - Who's the guy with Nemerov?
会面顺利　　　老尼身旁的是谁？
- Anatoli Grushkov. - Old KGB?
古东尼　　　前苏联特务？
He's been around since Brezhnev. Nobody's had the guts to get rid of him.
他是老臣子，没人敢动他分毫
Because he knows where the bodies are buried?
因为他知道尸体葬在哪里？
He probably buried them himself.
也许是他亲手下葬的
And we were able to obtain a roster of their scientists at Arzamas.
我们有阿尔扎马斯科学家的名册
Who's who, what their expertise is.
列明他们的身分、专长
Arzamas-16 is home
阿尔扎马斯十六区
to the All-Russian Scientific Research Institute of Experimental Physics
是俄国实验物理学科研所之乡
and is the birthplace of our first atomic bomb.
也是我国首个原子弹的诞生地
Many of our greatest scientists worked here and many still do.
不少伟大科学家还在这里工作
Since 1995,
自1995年…
we have dismantled over 10,000 nuclear devices.
我们已拆除逾一万个核武装置
We tried so hard to get in here over the years.
多年来我们千方百计想进来这儿
I sent three people.
我派了三个人来
They all died trying.
他们都为此牺牲
What does the T-shirt say?
T血上写着什么？
"I am a bomb technician. If you see me running... try to catch up."
我是炸弹专家，见我跑…跟着跑
OK.
好的
Sir, I'm sorry. Just one quick thing. I'm sure it's nothing.
抱歉打岔，但我要问一件小事
According to this, there are 17 senior scientists on duty today.
这个说今天该有17位科学家当值
I only count 14.
我只数到14位
Doctors Milinov, Orlov and Spassky. They don't seem to be here.
三位博士，分别姓米、奥、史的
I will make inquiries.
这个我会查清楚
Dr Milinov is out sick. Orlov is on vacation.
米博士病了，奥博士放假
Spassky, I'm grieved to say, was killed
史博士…很不幸已过世了
driving his car to work just this past week.
上周开车上班时遇上意外
We move on, shall we?
我们继续吧？
Please.
这边走
Very impressive. You almost seem to have that information memorised.
真棒，这一切你都记得一清二楚
I assumed you would ask, Dr Ryan.
早料到你会问这个
We touch down at Andrews at 2130. Tell him to meet me there.
我们九点半下飞机，叫他来会合
Sir? Those three missing scientists.
局长，那三位没出现的科学家
Milinov's expertise is detonators.
姓米的擅长造雷管
Spassky's expertise is the nuclear core.
姓史的善于造核子武器
Orlov is a mathematician
姓奥的是个数学家
whose expertise is the geometry of high explosives inside a fission bomb.
擅长计算裂变弹的炸药用量
The exact three men you would need if you wanted to build a bomb.
要造核弹就要找这三个人
- Grushkov said... - Grushkov's a liar.
老古说…　　老古是个大话王
Milinov is not sick. Orlov hardly ever takes a vacation
姓米的没病，姓奥的没放假
and Spassky, who's supposed to have died driving a car, doesn't drive.
撞车死掉的史博士根本不懂开车
They have no idea where these guys are.
他们不知道这三人的下落
I'm dying to ask you how you know.
但你却无所不知
Secure source inside the Kremlin.
是克里姆林宫的线报
Codename Spinnaker.
代号斯纳加
He gives me stuff, I give him stuff.
我们互通情报
We keep the back channels open in hopes of staving off disaster.
打开秘密渠道，以免灾难发生
And speaking of disaster, did you call your girlfriend yet?
说起灾难，你联络了女友没有？
No. I don't know how to get out of this.
不，我不知道该怎样解释
All right. Invite her to the White House correspondents dinner Sunday night.
请她出席周日晚白宫的记者晚宴
It's the hottest ticket in town.
那是城中的盛会
- Sounds great. How do I get in? - Trust me.
好主意，我如何入场　　　相信我
I'll see you at the car.
在车上再见
Still loving your desk job?
还喜欢你的文职工作吗？
Yeah, I am.
是的
How's your Russian?
你的俄语还管用吗？
Still works. Why?
还管用，为什么？
Three Russian nuclear scientists are missing. I need to know where they are.
俄国科学家失踪，要找他们下落
I wasn't doing this any more.
我不再做这种工作了
I just need information this time, Johnny.
我只是想要这些资料，约翰
Your orders are on the plane. Wheels up at 2330. Have a nice flight.
指令在飞机上，十一点半起飞
Sunday night, 8.00, at the Hilton. The tickets are in the name of John Clark.
周日晚八点，希尔顿酒店
- You do have a tux? - Yeah, yes, sir.
你有礼服吧？　　有的，局长
My beautiful wife, Julie, is from New Jersey. 15 electoral votes.
我的妻子茱莉来自新泽西
And is, as you know, half-Jewish,
大家都知道她是半个犹太人
so we'll take Florida's 25 electoral votes and divide by two.
所以我们把佛州25张票平分
- This is a nice hotel. - Yeah. Beautiful.
这酒店很棒　　　很华丽
My friend Rita stayed here once. She said it was... nice.
丽达曾入住这酒店…说很不错
Maybe after dinner we can...
也许晚宴结束后…
...we can get a room here.
我们在这里租一间房
I already did.
我已订了房间
- You didn't. - Yes, I did.
你没有　　　我有
...I did, on a handful of occasions, smoke marijuana.
我曾在多个场合抽过大麻
California, 54 electoral votes.
加州，54张选举团选票
At 0600 Moscow time, the Russians launched a massive artillery strike
莫斯科时间六点钟，俄军向车臣
against Grozny, the capital of Chechnya.
首都格罗兹尼施以猛烈炮击
The shells contained an experimental chemical weapon, a nerve agent.
炮弹含有实验性生化武器的神经性毒气
Saturation, you can see on the sat photos, took 20 minutes,
依图片所示，20分钟后毒气扩散
after which every person inside a radius of 12 miles
方圆12哩内的所有人都会…
was rendered helpless by symptoms approximating late-stage cerebral palsy.
欲救无从，出现大脑麻痹的症状
- Oh, my God. - How many dead?
老天　　　死了多少人？
Best guess, 80%.
该有八成人
Nemerov launched the biggest attack in the history of chemical warfare.
老尼发动历来最大型的生化战
- Let's talk response. - The worst thing we can do is nothing.
谈对策吧　　　最糟的是毫无对策
If he gets away with chemical weapons, what's next? Biological, nuclear?
若他得逞，下次会是核战吧？
OK. Short of gassing the Kremlin, what's the strongest response?
除了以毒攻毒，还有什么法子？
- We send in peacekeepers. - Chechnya's not sovereign.
派出和平部队　　　车臣没有主权
They requested recognition, so we give it. Not full diplomatic, provisional.
他们想建立地位，我们如其所愿
Then the Chechens request assistance and we send in peacekeepers.
于是车臣要求协助，我们就派军
- How do you get them in there? - We fly them in from Turkey.
怎样去那儿　　　从土耳其飞过去
- Over Armenian air space? - To screw Russia? They won't complain.
飞越美国领空？
Let's do it. Nemerov can choke on it.
动手吧，还老尼一点颜色
Bill?
比尔？
- Dr Ryan. - Yes, sir.
雷博士　　　是的，局长
What do you think?
你有何高见？
Conventional wisdom suggests
守旧派会建议
that Nemerov is playing the traditional Russian role:
老尼沿用旧有方法，老调重弹
Be aggressive, flex your muscles, dare the world to stop you.
要有野心，扩展势力，威吓全球
- But Nemerov isn't conventional. - He acts like a hardliner.
但老尼不吃这套　　　他是强硬派
With respect, I don't think he is one.
无意冒犯，我不同意这看法
He just gassed the capital of another country. With respect, you're wrong.
他刚攻打别国首都，所以你错了
- So what are we wasting our time for? - What if he didn't order the attack?
为何浪费时间？
What if Nemerov didn't order the attack?
若不是他下令攻车臣呢？
What if it was a... a rogue general?
如果是掌权的上将在搞鬼呢？
Or a military unit frustrated they couldn't get the rebels out of the city?
或是党军不满，赶不走市内的叛兵
Have you reason to believe he didn't order it, or are you just floating this?
你有实据支持此说，还是在胡扯？
You don't know.
你不能肯定
I don't think he did it, sir. I would bet he didn't do it.
该是这样，我敢说他没下令施袭
Will senior staff remain behind for a few minutes, please?
请高级官员多留一会儿？
Russia's newly-installed president, Alexander Nemerov,
俄罗斯新任总统尼艾历…
has just begun to address the state. We join him in progress.
刚开始发表演说，以下是直播
For ten years now, we have contended...
十年来我们一直对抗…
Excuse me. Could you turn that up?
麻烦你开大声点？
...toward innocent Russian citizens.
伤害无辜的俄罗斯百姓
Finally...
终于…
...every nation has a right to defend itself.
每一个国家都有权自卫
This terrorism must end.
这种恐怖活动必须被遏止
The bombing of Chechnya... was my decision.
轰炸车臣…是我的决定
Nice going, ace.
做得好，醒目仔
Who did it?
是谁做的？
General Pildysh, General Mitkin. Unhappy old Communists.
皮上将、苗上将，共产老头不悦
Bastards.
混蛋
- Relieve them of command. - I will shoot them myself.
解除其军职　　　我会亲自杀他们
Just disappear them.
使他们消失就是
Their execution would tell the world I didn't have control.
处决他们会显得我不是大权在握
These days, better to appear guilty than impotent.
现在表现内疚比表现无能为佳
How is our Russian friend affected by this?
我们的俄国朋友受到影响吗？
I am not affected. I remain devoted to our little plan.
没有，我仍然支持这个计划
At what you're charging us, I am not surprised.
以你的收费，我才不感到意外
- And the American? - Mr Mason is a believer.
美国佬呢？　　马先生相信我们
I put a little extra in the escrow account for him.
我已多存了一点钱进他的户口
- Why? - He won't live long enough to get it.
为什么？　　他不会有太长的命
- Where is the package? - It left Haifa a week ago.
货呢？　　一周前从海法寄出
I'm told these things can kill you.
早就说这些东西可以致命
But so much has changed.
但是事情有变
Perhaps the new situation suggests we consider... a different approach?
也许在新形势上该用…新方法？
Maybe try to bring Russia more into Europe,
也许试着令俄罗斯融入欧洲
more into our way of thinking?
更接纳我们的想法？
We have discussed that, Monsieur Monceau,
这个我们早已讨论过
and with your concurrence, rejected it.
而且你也同意不那么做
Oh. Perhaps we were hasty.
也许我们这次太鲁莽
- Perhaps our plan is... - Is what?
也许计划…　　怎样？
Not perfectly conceived.
进行得不顺利
Are you crazy? All over the world, right-wing parties,
你疯了吗？全世界的右翼组织…
nationalist movements, Nazis, Aryan Nations,
民族主义者、纳粹、反犹太国家
all working together for the first time.
首次并肩合作
Is that not perfect?
这还不算顺利？
Well, I respect the will and judgment of my friends.
我尊重朋友们的意愿和判断
But in light of the week's events, I am grown...
但这周发生的事令我…
...uncomfortable with this plan.
对这计划失去信心
So I must... beg your leave.
所以我必须…请辞了
Gentlemen.
各位再见
Herr Haft will help you out.
哈夫会送你出去
Your scarf, monsieur.
你的颈巾
Watch it with that thing. You're gonna kill somebody.
小心开这个，否则会害死人
Yo, what's up, Mason?
你好吗？阿马
You know, I always wanted to ask you... Where'd you get that tat, man?
我一直想问你在哪里弄的这个纹身
The navy.
海军
The navy? I was in the navy.
海军？我也曾当过海军
Hospital ship, six years. You?
在医务船六年，你呢？
Eight months.
八个月
Oh. You wash out?
你退役了？
All right, brother. You have a good one.
好吧，兄弟，晚安
Yeah, brother.
好的，兄弟
...not realising the rest of the world is watching and will take a cue from us...
没发觉其他国家会以我们为榜样
The unprecedented attack on Chechnya
车臣遭受空前残暴的袭击
signals a dangerous and troubling shift in Russian policy.
显示俄政府新班子面对不稳之局
It demands the toughest and most unambiguous response from the West.
西方需作出最强硬鲜明的反应
NATO forces are on their way to Chechnya to serve as peacekeepers
北约和平部队正前往车臣
and to provide humanitarian aid to victims of this monstrous...
为这个大灾难的受害者提供援助
I expected this.
早料到会如此
Really?
是吗？
What will you do?
你会怎么做？
Nothing.
没什么
We will do nothing.
我们什么都不做
These are four hours old. Russian 12th, 15th and 2nd tank regiments.
照片拍了四个钟
Why haven't they moved?
为何有调动？
- Nemerov's too smart to move them. - He speaks.
老尼不会这么笨　　　但他已表态
Jack, Nemerov's got, like, 19,000 tanks. No way NATO can match that.
他有近两万部坦克，北约无法比
That's why he's not gonna move them.
所以他才不会调动坦克
It's like chess. He's thinking three moves ahead.
这就像下棋，要事先部署好
The NATO playbook says we can only stop him with tactical nuclear weapons.
北约说我们只能用核武克制他
And he won't risk a nuclear war over this.
他才不会为此引发核战
I also think he's sending us a message. He didn't bomb Grozny.
他该是有所暗示，他没攻击车臣
Excuse me. I'm looking for Mrs Spassky.
打扰了，请问史老太太在哪儿？
At the end of the corridor.
在走廊尽头那边
I haven't seen Sasha since university.
毕业后我没见他了
And you were his teaching assistant? Strange, I don't remember you.
你是他的助教？我却记不起你
When he heard I was in Arzamas, he asked me to look in on you.
他知道我在这区，叫我来探望你
- He says he'll take me to the West. - That would require a lot of money.
他说带我去西方　　　所费不菲
Just because the imbeciles here pay him nothing doesn't mean others won't.
这儿赚不到钱，可去别处赚
He has a secret job.
他有一份秘密工作
For the government?
替政府做事？
For imbeciles with money.
替有钱的笨蛋做事
Same nonsense, do this, don't do that.
同一番废话，做这个，别做那个
They even told him not to call his mother.
他们还叫他别联络母亲
The pigs.
混蛋
I could die any day and he can't phone his mother.
我随时归西，他却不能来电话
But my Sasha, he called.
但我的儿子好孝顺
Just last night.
昨晚才来过电话
Clark got us her number. NSA traced calls to that number back to here.
阿勒取得她的号码
It's an abandoned Soviet army base on the Kremenchug reservoir.
克列缅兵格水库的前苏联基地
What are three Russian atomic scientists doing in Ukraine?
三个俄国科学家在乌克兰干嘛？
A fair guess, they're building a bomb.
该是在制造核弹
Nemerov has thousands of bombs. Why would he build a secret one?
老尼有无数核弹，为何建这个？
Deniability.
为了否认一切
Build one nobody knows about, he can drive it to Chechnya in his Beemer.
秘密造一个，然后偷运去车臣
No way to track it, no way to trace it.
无法追查，瞒天过海
He could set it off and say, "I didn't do it."
他可以引爆核弹，然后矢口否认
With respect, I don't think that adds up.
无意冒犯，但这说不通
It adds up. You just don't like what it adds up to.
说得通，只是你不喜欢这结果
Ah, the warmth of plutonium decay.
铀腐蚀的热度
It's completely corroded. At least you're wearing gloves.
这个腐蚀严重，幸好你有戴手套
Anyone want to light up an American cigarette?
有人想抽一根美国烟吗？
You're crazy.
你这疯子
I'm going out.
我出去吸烟
The explosive blocks must be replaced.
要更换炸药块
Machined to a thousandth of a millimetre
配置经过精密计算的系统
in a mathematically determined configuration.
细小至千分之一毫米
- Do we have a bomb? - First we must analyse the yield...
可造核弹吗？　　首先要分析…
Do we have a bomb?
可造核弹吗？
Yes.
可以
Yes, we do.
可造核弹
This is a... a test.
这是一个…考验
Answer it.
接电话吧
- Answer it. - Are you sure?
快去　　　真的要我接？
Hello?
喂？
Yes.
是的
Yes, sir.
是的，局长
I have to go outside for just a second.
我要出去一会儿
OK? I'll be right back.
好吗？我马上回来
I'll be right back.
很快回来
- Sir, I write reports. - I reviewed your military records.
我负责写报告　　　你有当兵经验
- You can take care of yourself. - Yes, sir. But I'm not trained for that.
懂得自卫　　　对，但我不是特务
I'm not asking you to be an operations officer, just my eyes and ears. I can't go.
你要做我的耳目，不是做特务
So... this isn't sanctioned.
那么…这行动未经批准
I want you to give this to Clark, see what he finds out, bring it home.
这个交给阿勒，拿他的情报回来
Yes, sir.
是的，局长
Jack...
杰克…
...we never had this discussion.
我们从未有过这番对话
What discussion?
什么对话？
OK. Clark... So this is three days ago.
阿勒…三天前
It shows vehicles here. Guards here and here.
这儿有车，这两处有守卫
I gotta get one of those.
我也该买一部这个
Now, the infrared satellite took this photograph 34 hours ago.
红外线卫星在34小时前拍到这个
That shows guards here and here.
显示这两处有守卫
I don't even have e-mail.
我甚至不用电邮
There are two at the checkpoint, between two and five in the barracks
检查站有两人，军营有二至五人
and two with the package, which we believe to be here.
两人有武器，而我们会在这里
No problem. Give me a couple of guys, some tranquilliser darts,
没问题，给我两个人和麻醉枪
we can be out in six minutes.
六分钟就可以离开
- There is a problem. - What's that?
有问题的　　　什么问题？
This is yesterday. No guards visible at all.
这是昨天的情形，一个守卫都没有
Why is that a problem, Mr Ryan?
那为何是个问题？
For two reasons. Either we can't see them, which is bad,
两个原因，糟的是看不见敌人
or worse, they left, and we're too late.
更糟的是他们已走，我们来迟了
Suit up.
快换衣服
- What? - You can't go dressed like that.
什么？　　你不能穿成这样
No, no. I'm an analyst. I don't go on missions.
不，我是分析员，不做特务工作
Relax, 007. It's not a mission. It's just a recce.
放心，007，这只是侦察工作
OK, fine, whatever you call it. I don't do that. I just write reports.
随你怎么说，我只负责写报告
OK. So write a report about it. Suit up.
那就为此写报告，换衣服
Clark, no.
阿勒，不行
So, Cabot tells me you got my ticket to the correspondents dinner.
老卡说你代我出席记者晚宴
Have a good time? I've never been to one of those.
好玩吗？我从未见过那种大场面
I was actually looking forward to it.
其实我满怀期待赴会的
Clark, no. I'm not going in there.
不，我不会进去
Goddamn right. You're gonna stay here and make sure no one steals my boat.
当然，你留在这里帮我看这只艇
Be right back.
马上就回来
Damn.
糟了
Oh, Jesus.
老天
Oh, God. Immigration didn't call you guys, huh?
真是的，入境处没通知你们吗？
I'm sorry. You speak English? I don't speak much Ukrainian.
抱歉，会说英语吗？
It's not what you think. I'm an American citizen. I have my papers...
别误会，我是美国公民，有证件…
OK. No papers.
好了，不出示证件
Please. Just put the gun down.
请你把抢放下
The light? You want me to put the light down?
电筒？你想我把它放下？
OK. Take it easy. I'll put the light down.
别胡来，我会把电筒放下
Here we go, I'm putting it down.
好了，我把电筒放下
Shoot him, Ryan.
开枪，杰克
Shoot him.
快开枪
Shoot him before he figures out what I'm saying.
趁他未猜出我说什么，快开枪
- Get their shoes. - What?
叫他们脱鞋　　　什么？
Tell them to take their shoes off.
叫他们脱鞋
- You speak Ukrainian. - Yeah. You don't?
你会说乌克兰话　　　你不懂？
Whatever it is they were spray painting was big, about the size of a fridge.
他们喷油的东西该有雪柜那么大
The imprint it left was deep. So we know three things.
印痕很深，所以我们知道三件事
It was heavy, something was radioactive, and now it's gone.
它很重，有辐射性，还不见了
- One of them spoke English? - South African.
其中一人说英语？　　南非人
So, what's a South African doing in the Ukraine
那他在乌克兰跟三个俄国科学家
with three Russian scientists and a crate from Israel?
和一个以色列货箱有何关系？
- Tell Cabot I'll call him from Haifa. - I have a feeling you better hurry.
我会去海法找老卡　　　事不宜迟
Most people believe the 20th century was defined by the death struggle
不少人认为，20世纪是共产主义…
of communism versus capitalism
和资本主义之争
and that fascism was but a hiccup.
而法西斯主义只是昙花一现
Today we know better.
如今我们更有体会
Communism was a fool's errand. The followers of Marx, gone from this earth.
共产主义徒劳无功
But the followers of Hitler abound and thrive.
但希特勒的信众则日益增强
Hitler, however, had one great disadvantage.
不过，希特勒生不逢时
He lived in a time when fascism, like a virus,
当时，法西斯主义像病毒般散播
like the AIDS virus,
好比爱滋病病毒
needed a strong host in order to spread. Germany was that host.
要有强大的受体以便散播
But strong as it was, Germany could not prevail.
可是即使德国强大，但还是失败
The world was too big.
这世界太大了
Fortunately, the world has changed.
幸好世界改变了
Global communications, cable TV, the internet.
全球通讯、有线电视、互联网
Today the world is smaller
如今世界变小了
and the virus does not need a strong host in order to spread.
而病毒不用强大受体帮助扩散
This virus...
这种病毒…
...is airborne.
可在空气中散播
One more thing. Let no man call us crazy.
还有一点，别让人家说我们疯狂
They called Hitler crazy, but Hitler wasn't crazy. He was stupid.
他们说希特勒疯狂，其实他是笨
You don't fight Russia and America.
你不用跟美俄对敌
You get Russia and America to fight each other
令美俄打起来就是
and destroy each other.
令他们互相残杀
- What did you find? - Ukraine's exports are online.
有何发现？　　乌克兰出口贸易
I pulled up the shipping manifests.
我查过这两周的运货单
The only crate that size was picked up at Kiev International ten days ago
那货箱在十天前送抵基辅机场
and flown to the Canary Islands.
再运去加那利群岛
The air force has a nuclear assessment team. Call them...
空军有核武评估小组，叫他们…
Jack, it got put on a cargo freighter, headed for the East Coast.
那货箱上了货机，送去东岸了
- What? - Baltimore. It's coming here.
什么？　　 巴尔的摩，送来这儿
It's a great view from the Budweiser blimp as we count down to game time.
飞船外景色一流，球赛快将开始
We'll have the pre-game festivities
赛前活动多姿多采
as well as the arrival of the nation's number one football fan in a moment.
而全国头号球迷也快将到场
Then conquer we must
∮誓要达成目标∮
For our cause it is just
∮全因这是正义的使命∮
And this be our motto
∮我们以此为座右铭∮
In God is our trust
∮相信上帝∮
And the star-spangled banner
∮满布星号的旗帜∮
Forever shall wave
∮永远飘扬∮
O'er the land of the free...
∮在自由的国土上…∮
Get me the duty officer!
快联络值勤官！
Home of the brave
∮勇者之乡∮
Ladies and gentlemen, the President of the United States,
各位，有请美国总统
Robert Fowler!
霍罗拔！
Showtime.
要出场了
Shit.
可恶
15 yard penalty, first down.
15码罚球，第一个死球
That's the way!
打得好！
Shit.
混帐
Hello.
喂
- Hello? - Sir!
喂？　　局长！
Shit!
该死！
- Cabot. - It's Ryan.
比尔・卡伯特　　　是杰克
- What? - The bomb is in play.
什么事？　　核弹已送来
The AFRAT team are meeting me at the docks in 20 minutes to try to find it.
搜索队20分钟后在码头跟我会合
- What docks? - Baltimore.
什么码头？　　 巴尔的摩
- You're breaking up. What did you say?
什么？你说什么？　　 巴尔的摩
- I'm losing you. I'll call you back... - Baltimore.
我待会给你电话　　　巴尔的摩
Sir!
局长！
John! Red-Green! Let's go! Let's go!
阿尊、红组、绿组，快走！
Move it! Let's go!
快送总统走！
Move! Go, go, go, go! Move!
赶快！快走！
What the hell is going on?
怎么回事？
Some Russian scientists made a nuclear bomb. It's arrived in Baltimore.
俄国佬制造了核弹，还送来这儿
- Get those people out of the stadium. - Stay down!
快疏散观众　　　趴下来！
The President has been taken off the field.
总统突然被护送离场
- 407. - Thanks, JJ.
407号　　　劳驾
Clearly something has happened of tremendous proportions.
显然发生了大规模的爆炸
We have no word as to what but there is an enormous cloud over...
起因不明，但空中有一大团云…
Go, go, go!
快走！
Mr President! Are you all right?
总统先生，你没事吧？
He's stuck. Get out of the way.
他被困在车内，走开
Are you all right, Mr President? This is the marines, sir.
你没事吧？我们是海军陆战队
I need your help, Danny.
丹尼，过来帮忙
Alvarez, get me a stretcher, now!
艾华，快拿担架来！
You got the stretcher?
你拿担架来
- You got the stretcher? - No, I don't want one.
你拿担架来　　　不用了
Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
快走…
Move it!
快走！
Go, go! Close them off! Go on up!
赶快！行了！起飞！
Mr President...
总统先生…
There's been a nuclear explosion in America. You must come with us now.
美国发生核爆，请你马上来
What?
什么？
We don't know who or how. But it wasn't us.
不知谁在搞鬼，但肯定不是我们
After Grozny you hope it wasn't us.
继格罗兹尼…你希望不是我们做
We are drafting a strong denial for you.
正草拟一份声明让你作强烈否认
And a statement of sympathy.
还要表示慰问的
And Yuri... order all military on the alert.
尤里…下令三军作好戒备
Hey! It's Ryan.
是杰克！
- Jack, where are you? - Somewhere outside Baltimore.
你在哪里？　　 巴尔的摩市外
- Cabot got the President out. - Where is he now?
老卡救了总统　　　他在哪儿？
They're taking him airborne, on NAOC. They think it might be the Russians.
他会留在飞机上
It wasn't the Russians. I gotta talk to Cabot. Patch me through to the plane.
不是，我要找老卡，帮我联络他
Cabot's not on the plane. We don't know where he is. Call back in an hour.
他不在机上
We don't have an hour. Fowler's gonna want to hit back now.
时间无多，总统随时准备还击
Listen. We have to prove it wasn't the Russians before he's convinced it is.
要赶快向他证明，这不是俄军做的
Can you get back to Langley?
你可以回来兰利吗？
There's no time. The radiation assessment team, where are they?
没时间，辐射评估小组在哪里？
Stambler Tunnels, south of the city.
市区南面的斯谭拿隧道
The prevailing winds are blowing the fallout to the east and north.
正在吹盛行风，东、北还有落尘
As long as you stay south you're OK.
你留在南面就较安全
- Mr President, are you all right? - How the hell do you think I am?
你没事吧？　　你说呢？
- How many casualties? - We don't know.
有多少伤亡？　　不知道
- How the hell did it get there? - We don't know. Radar didn't pick it up.
核弹怎么来的　　　雷达侦测不到
- Well, how is Cabot? Where is he? - I don't know.
老卡呢？他在哪里　　　我不知道
- What do you know? - I don't know, all right? I don't know!
那你知道什么？　　我一无所知
I don't know!
我一无所知！
- General, Kondor is not on board. - Send the AFRAT team.
康达没上机　　　派搜索队去找
Mr President, I recommend we move to DEFCON-2.
总统，我建议进入二级紧急状态
Where's our intelligence?
我们的情报如何？
Russian air defences are at their highest level.
俄国空军防御处于最高戒备状态
Maybe they're afraid of being attacked. I can't get this goddamn chair open!
他们或怕遇袭，我拉不开这张椅
We're about to take off.
准备起飞
- We don't know who did it... - We think the Russians...
不知是谁搞鬼　　　应该是俄军…
- You think? - Sir, DEFCON-2.
该是？　　进入二级紧急状态吧
- We're groping in the dark... - This is too much goddamn bullshit!
我们在揣测…　　　都是废话！
And not enough fact.
还不够证据
The blast crater is about 100, 150 yards wide,
弹坑有100至150码那么大
which suggests a low-yield device,
这核弹威力不是太大
quite a bit smaller than the Hiroshima bomb.
比落在广岛的原子弹还要小
A quarter of a square mile around the stadium is just gone.
球场周围四分一平方哩之地被毁
Beyond that, buildings remain, heavily damaged, for another quarter mile.
外围的大厦没倒塌，但损毁严重
The damage tapers off the farther you get from Ground Zero.
离核爆区越远，破坏越小
Dubinin.
都宾
Herr Haft has left for America. Now we are counting on you.
哈夫去了美国，现在就靠你了
I assure you, I will earn every pfennig.
我保证我物有所值
Attention.
立正！
You've heard of the bomb in the USA.
你们也知道美国发生核爆
What you haven't heard is that 15 minutes ago
但你们不知道15分钟前
an American ICBM hit Moscow.
美国发射洲际弹道导弹攻莫斯科
We are to retaliate against an American aircraft carrier in the North Sea.
我们要打美军在北海的航空母舰
Man your aircraft.
快准备出动
The ash isn't radioactive. The winds are blowing the fallout to sea.
灰烬没有辐射性
Captain. Jack Ryan, CIA.
上尉，中情局杰克・雷恩
Lorna Shiro. You need to wait outside.
冼罗娜，你要在外边等
I need to know all you know about the bomb.
把你对核弹所知的都告诉我
We're collecting samples. Get in line and we'll have the report out tomorrow.
我们在采集样本，明天会有公布
Captain, I need to know now where this bomb came from,
上尉，我要知道核弹从哪儿来的
or even where it didn't come from or there may not be a tomorrow.
或是它不是从哪来，否则没明天
Shit. Wesson, where are you?
混帐，阿韦，你在哪里？
About a quarter mile from Ground Zero.
离核爆区四分之一哩
This is about as far as we'll go. My feet are sizzling.
已尽力而为，脚板快被烤熟了
I'm getting rads nearly the limit of our gear.
辐射度接近装备所能抵御的上限
- OK. Cut the rover loose and get out. - Roger that.
小队马上撤退　　　收到
Dillon, the crate the bomb was shipped in. Somebody had to sign for it at port.
装核弹的货箱在码头该有人签收
Customs must have a database. Get me a name. Where's Cabot?
海关定有记录，老卡在哪里？
No one knows. We're checking the hospitals.
不知所踪，我们在查看各医院
- Have you tried Memorial? - He wouldn't be there.
找过纪念医院？　　他不在那里
No, I mean... Is it still...
不，我是指医院没…
It's Cathy's hospital.
那是卡丝工作的医院
As far as I know it's still there, but the phones are down.
医院没被炸毁，但电话失灵
All right. Can you keep checking? Thanks.
请你继续追查，麻烦你
They could have launched a cruise missile.
他们本可以发射巡航导弹
- We don't know that this is Russia. - We don't know it's not.
不肯定是俄军所为　　　但也许是
If they were sending us a message, they'd want us to know it was them.
若他们要我们知难而退
Except they could inspire the confusion we're going through now.
除了他们想故弄玄虚，声东击西
Mr President, we're uplinked.
总统先生，准备好通讯了
President Nemerov, there's been a major nuclear event in the United States.
尼总统，美国发生严重核爆事件
Loss of life is severe.
死伤惨重
- It was no accident. - It was not an accident.
这绝不是意外　　　这绝不是意外
We don't yet know where it came from, we don't...
我们还不知道核弹从哪儿来…
We have not yet ascertained the source of this weapon. Rest assured...
我们还没确定核弹的来源…
We have not yet ascertained the source of this weapon.
我们还没确定核弹的来源
But rest assured those responsible will be dealt with most severely.
但可保证，我国定将严惩真凶
He's fishing.
他在试探我们
Send our reply.
给他回复
Whoa, that was a little fast.
这么快有回应
"Please accept the deepest sympathies of the Russian people."
请接受俄国人民最深切的慰问
"If it was deliberate, this is a crime without precedent."
若是蓄意施袭，诚是空前的暴行
"What madman would do such a thing and for what purpose?"
是哪个疯子所为？目的何在？
"You must believe that Russia had nothing to do with this infamous act."
敬请相信俄国与此暴行绝无关连
It's canned. He prepared that in advance.
是预谋，他早有此着
President Nemerov, we've no reason to suspect Russian involvement...
尼总统，如今我们无理由怀疑
...at this time...
俄国与此事有关
...but we will protect ourselves from further aggression.
但我们会竭力自卫，免再受袭击
He thinks we did this.
他认为是我们做的
We must demonstrate the strength of our weapons.
我们必须显示军力
They have to understand that attacking Russia would be suicide.
让他们明白攻打俄国就是找死
Increase the alert status.
加强戒备
TAO, EW. I'm picking up intermittent radar, bearing 020.
接收到间断的讯号，方位020
Where?
哪儿？
Now it's gone.
没有了
There. It's a weak signal.
这儿，但讯号微弱
TAO, inbound contact.
有敌机来袭
Multiples on the same bearing.
相同方位有多架敌机
- Vampire, vampire! - Fast movers inbound.
注意！　　敌机迅速来袭
I got seven, eight, nine of them!
有七、八、九架敌机！
The missiles definitely came from Russian aircraft.
导弹是从俄军战机发射的
Grennel thinks he can save the ship, but flight ops are out.
母舰还保得住，但不能执行任务
I ordered no such attack.
我没下令攻打航空母舰
You must not respond to this action until we investigate all possibilities.
请保持冷静，先让我们调查清楚
"...until we investigate all possibilities."
先让我们调查清楚
Like you did in Chechnya?
正如车臣事件？
Mr President, who is in control of your armed forces?
尼总统，谁在控制你的军队？
You dropped the bomb on Hiroshima.
是你们在广岛投掷原子弹
You dropped the bomb on Nagasaki.
是你们在长崎投掷原子弹
Do not lecture me on Chechnya.
别拿车臣事件来教训我
"...lecture me on Chechnya."
拿车臣事件来教训我
Mr President, we are now at a de facto state of war with the Russians.
事实上现在我们已跟俄国开战
John Clark was in Haifa yesterday. We have to find him right away.
昨天勒约翰在海法，定要找到他
Wow. Look at that gadolinium reading.
看看钆的含量读数
Yeah. The mass fraction is huge.
质量数很高
OK, connect me to Dillon. I'll hold.
快联络迪伦，我会等
There it is. Savannah River.
就在这儿，萨凡纳河
- Oh, yeah. - Oh, yeah, what?
没错　　　什么没错？
They had a gadolinium problem.
那边有钆的问题
Hanford does it another way, and generate too much promethium.
汉福的做法不对，产生太多钇
Hold on. Can you translate that into English?
慢着，你可否解释清楚一点？
This plutonium came from the DOE plant at Savannah River, February '68,
68年2月铀来自河上这间工厂
from K reactor. We even know which part of K reactor.
源自K反应堆，还知道是哪部分
- Wait. This is our plutonium? - Made in the USA.
这是我们造的铀？　　美国产品
Dillon, you've got to find Cabot.
迪伦，我一定要找到老卡
Are you advocating we launch a first strike?
你想说服我们发动第一击？
It is not a first strike! There's already been a first strike, and a second.
不是！已经有第一击，事已至此
- Don't you get it? - No, I don't get it!
你还不明白　　　我不明白
I don't understand why we have to nuke them! It's not reasonable.
为何要用核弹？这不合理
Sidney, goddamn it!
悉尼，混帐！
They practically sank an aircraft carrier!
他们打沉我们的航空母舰！
Their missile silos are hot. We're getting bullshit from Nemerov.
他们准备开战，老尼又废话连篇
Let's not forget how this started. They tried to kill me, remember?
别忘了是谁先动手，他们要我死
Don't fucking tell me to be reasonable!
所以别劝我讲理！
Please come to the triage tent on the side of the building.
请来大厦旁边的鉴别分类营
We will help you find who you are looking for,
我们协助你找伤者
but we are low on blood supply.
但我们的血包供应不足
Sir?
局长？
Hi.
你好
What?
什么？
- President? - The President's fine.
总统？　　他平安无恙
He's fine. Sir...
他没事，局长…
The bomb. The plutonium...
那核弹，铀元素
- Wife. - What?
太太　　　什么？
Wife.
太太
Your wife? I'm sure she's fine. She's in DC.
你太太？她没事，在华盛顿
The blast radius wasn't that...
核爆范围不是…
...it wasn't that wide.
那么大
Sir, listen to me.
局长，听我说
The plutonium was ours.
那些铀是我们的
John Clark's in Haifa to track down the arms dealer. I can't get hold of him.
阿勒去追查军火商，我找不到他
I don't know what to do.
我不知道该怎么办
Girl... girlfriend.
女…女朋友
She...
她…
She works in Baltimore, so...
她在巴尔的摩工作，所以…
...I don't know.
我不清楚
Spinnaker.
斯纳加
- What? - Spinnaker.
什么？　　斯纳加
Sir?
局长？
Bill?
比尔？
Yeah. We found the receiver address for the crate.
我们查到接收货箱的人的地址
Port of Baltimore. Can you get to the docks?
巴尔的摩港口，你可以去码头吗
Find the Transcon warehouse. The name on the manifest is Mason.
找捷运货仓，收货人姓马
Sorry, I need this truck.
对不起，我急需这部车
Come on.
拜托
Shit.
混帐
Sir, we've come up with another alternative.
总统，我们想到另一个对策
A conventional attack on the airbase where the carrier attack originated.
反攻发动袭击航空母舰的空军基地
- It's a measured response. - Non-nuclear.
有限度的还击　　　不用核武
- Is it strong enough? - Smart bombs and F-16s.
够强烈吗　　　灵巧弹和F16战机
Can't afford for them to see us as weak.
我们绝不能示弱
They've got to know we have the guts to take it to the next level.
要让他们知道我们绝不好惹的
I think they'll get that message.
他们会明白这一点
Hit 'em.
动手吧
Eagles Nest, this is Eagle One. We have target acquired. Target is lit.
鹰巢，这是一号，我们瞄准目标
To make no response is to invite a greater attack.
不作反击就等于坐以待毙
American submarines from Norfolk and Kings Bay are putting to sea.
诺福克和金斯湾的潜艇已出动
They carry Trident D3 missiles. A first strike weapon.
载有D3三叉式导弹，第一击武器
Fowler is not so insane as to launch a first strike.
老霍不会疯得发动第一击
Perhaps he doesn't think it's the first strike.
也许他不认为这是第一击
Once their Stealth bombers go up, we will have no choice.
他们出动轰炸机，我们就没选择
That will be the sign.
这会是个征兆
How do we convince him not to launch his bombers?
怎么说服他别出动轰炸机？
- Maybe we should... - Bring our missiles to highest alert.
我们该…　　导弹处于高度戒备
They'd be crazy to attack then.
那他们一定是疯了才会施袭
Can I have your attention?
请各位注意
The generator has gone out.
发电机失灵
There's broken glass everywhere. Stay where you are. We will get back to...
四处是玻璃碎，别乱动，我们…
OK, fine. Please, stay where you are. We'll get you one by one.
好了，别乱动，我们会照料你们
Sir, can you hear me? Can you feel your arms and legs?
你听见吗？手脚有知觉吗？
A 9% IV and morphine drip. Sir, we're gonna take care of you.
9%静脉注射和吗啡滴注
What have you got?
这个伤者怎么样？
What do we do with the ones we know won't make it?
要是救不了的，应该怎么做？
Whatever we can.
尽力而为
What?
什么事？
Bill Cabot died.
比尔・卡伯特死了
I'm really sorry.
我很难过
This can't be happening.
不会是这样的
Sir, we have a call from Langley.
部长，兰利有电话来
Thank you.
劳驾
- Becker. - This is Jack Ryan.
阿贝　　　这是杰克・雷恩
Great. The Nemerov apologist.
太好了，是老尼的辩护者
Sir, this bomb was not Nemerov. I know this guy.
那核弹不是老尼的，我了解他
You said that after Grozny. Put it in your report.
车臣事件你也这么说，写报告吧
The plutonium...
那些铀…
Seems unusual to find radiation poisoning here.
没想到这儿会出现辐射污染
I have never seen such a thing.
这是前所未见的
That is why we published the case on the internet, to seek help.
所以我们在网上公布此事来求助
- How did he say it happened? - He will not talk about it.
他说起因是什么？　　他不肯说
Was anyone else exposed to the materials that made you sick?
其他人感染辐射令你病倒了？
Mr Ghazi, I'm not the police.
嘉先生，我不是警察
I'm a physician. I assure you anything you say stays between us.
我是医生，我会保守秘密
My friend and I find bomb.
我朋友和我找到一个核弹
We sell to a man who buys such things.
把它卖给一个军火商
Was it this man?
是这个人吗？
Other people may have come in contact with that bomb.
其他人也许接触过这核弹
We must help them.
我们要救他们
I am... going to die?
我…快要死吗
Yes?
是吗？
Yes.
是的
His name is Olson.
他叫奥森
He live in Damascus.
住在大马士革
Oh, yeah. We're getting it all.
行了，收到资料了
A nuclear strike on Colorado Springs would take out NORAD.
核武攻斯普林斯可破坏北美空防
It would limit their ability to launch a counter-attack.
那他们就不能够还击
How many people live in Colorado Springs?
斯普林斯有多少人口？
Three or four hundred thousand.
三、四十万人
Mr President, to use nuclear weapons against the Americans...
总统先生，用核武攻美国
...would be to cross a threshold.
就等于向他们宣战
They think we already have. Should we now wait for them to annihilate us?
他们早已这么想，我们等什么？
I cannot stop what I did not start.
不是我惹的祸我阻止不了
Mr President, we need you to initiate snapcount.
总统先生，你要下令采取行动
What happens then?
然后呢？
We prepare to take out their land-based missiles with a nuclear strike,
用核武摧毁他们陆上的导弹基地
find and kill their subs, knock out the planes they have on the ground
炸毁他们的潜艇或地上的飞机
and mobilise our fighters to destroy the ones they already have in the air.
还出动战机，攻击已在空中的敌军
What are our chances?
胜算有多大？
David?
大卫？
Odds are we leave Nemerov in a pretty pickle.
我们会令老尼陷于困境
He'll be left with, at best, a few hundred nukes,
他剩下的核弹最多有几百个
the ones we can't find.
那是我们找不到的
Mostly the... smaller, more mobile, less accurate kind.
它们较小型，易运送，没那么准
All those can do is target our cities.
而它们的目标会是我们的城市
But he knows to an absolute certainty that we will respond against his cities.
但他心知我们一定会以眼还眼
I spent my entire adult life wanting to be president.
我毕生想做一个总统
This is my presidency?
任期就此结束
Sir, I think he'll keep his 300 nukes as a deterrent against any future aggressor.
他会留三百个核弹以备不时之需
I think he'll push back from the table and call it a night.
这晚他应该会暂时就此罢手
I'm giving the order for snapcount. Maximum readiness.
我下令采取行动，准备用核武
Olson had wire payments of $45 million from someone named Dressler.
奥森收到斯拿4500万的汇款
Dillon, find out who Dressler is. Jack, I want you out of there.
快查这人底细…杰克，你快走
- I'm at the docks. - Look for the name Dressler.
我在码头　　　调查这个斯拿
No. Jack, get out. Dillon, call the Baltimore PD, give them the address.
杰克，你快走…给巴市警局这地址
- Wait for the cops. - I'll call you back.
等警察来　　　我会再联络你
Who's Dressler?
斯拿是什么人？
Where is he, goddamn it?
斯拿在哪里？可恶！
Where is Dressler?
斯拿在哪里？
Police! Put your hands up!
警察！举高双手！
- Where's Dressler? - Are you Jack Ryan?
斯拿在哪里？　　你是杰克・雷恩？
- Where's Dressler, goddamn it? - Let him go!
斯拿在哪里？　　放手
Where's Dressler? Where is he?
斯拿在哪里？快说？
Langley said you might need help.
兰利说你需要帮助
- I gotta get to the Pentagon. - I think I can help you with that.
我要去国防部　　　我可以帮你忙
Mr President.
总统先生
Their Stealth bombers have left Aviano.
他们的轰炸机已离开阿维艾诺
That is the sign.
他们有所行动
Shoot them down.
快把它们击落
God protect us.
愿主保佑
Mr President, they're scrambling their fighters. We're out of time.
他们的战机紧急起飞，时间无多
- Dave! - He has a heart condition.
大卫！　　他心脏病发
- Get a doctor. - Mr President.
快找医生　　　总统先生
- Where's your nitro? - I said get a doctor!
你的药呢　　　我说叫医生来
- Mr President. - Take him to my quarters.
总统先生　　　扶他去我的房间
Colonel, bring in the launch codes.
上校，拿系统密码机来
Dressler's an Austrian manufacturer, billionaire.
斯拿是奥地利商人，是亿万富翁
His father was executed at Nuremberg.
他父亲在纽伦堡被处决
He bought a seat in parliament and got booted out for saying pro-Nazi things.
他买到国会议席
Rudy, get me through to the President.
快让我跟总统说清楚
I can't do it, Jack. They're in the snapcount.
不行，他们正采取核武行动
- There's no way in. - Bullshit.
没法联络他们　　　废话
- I can do that for you, sir. - No, it's fine. Got some dirt on it.
让我帮你　　　不，卡上有泥巴
- Can I see it? We're on high alert. - I understand.
给我看，现在高度戒备　　　我知道
- Sir, put the card down. - Back off.
先生，把卡放下　　　退后
- I am ordering you... - Back off!
我命令你…　　　退后
Step back now! I am ordering you to take a step back! Put...
快停手！我命令你快停手！
General, there's a Dr Ryan from the CIA.
上将，中情局的杰克・雷恩来了
He wants to enter NMCC. He's unescorted.
他要求进入NMCC，他独自来的
- What's he want? - You, sir.
他想怎样？　　见你
I have a message from Director Cabot that I need to transmit over the hotline.
我要传达卡局长的口信给总统
- What's your authorisation? - I don't have one.
谁批准你这样做？　　没有人
- Where's Cabot? - Cabot's dead, sir.
卡局长呢？　　他已死了
- I need to get this information sent. - Not without authorisation. Get him out.
我要传口信
Wait! General! The President is basing his decisions on bad information!
上将！总统根据错误情报下决定
If you shut me out, your family and my family
若你不理我，你和我的家人
and 25 million other families will be dead in 30 minutes.
和2500万家庭会在半小时内丧命
My orders are to get this information to the people who make the decisions.
我的职责是给决策者准确的情报
I just need to send some information.
我只是想传达情报
What makes you think the President will listen to you?
总统为什么要听你说？
He doesn't have to.
他没此必要
How close are the bombers?
轰炸机有多接近？
They're slipping in and out of radar over Poland.
它们进出波兰上空
Activate the missile regiments.
出动导弹兵团
The launch sequence takes a minute to process after you give the order.
系统在你下令后，一分钟才启动
Before the order can be taken, an ID check must be performed.
下令前，要先核对身分
Mine is the... My number is...
我的号码是…
...the third one... third number down from the top.
数下来…第三个号码
Your orders, sir?
你的命令是什么？
- Strike. - I'm sorry, sir?
出击　　　抱歉，总统？
I give the order to strike.
我下令出击
Under the two-man rule, the order to strike must now be confirmed.
要马上作两人授命，下令出击
Bob, for the love of God.
罗拔，看在老天份上
Just do it.
动手好了
Sidney Owens, Secretary of State. It's the fourth number down.
国务卿奥悉尼，第四个号码
The order to strike has now been confirmed by the two-man rule.
已作了两人授命，下令出击
NMCC, strike order has been confirmed. Start the sequence.
出击的命令已确定，启动系统
- We've got activity on the hotline. - They've had their chance.
热线有动静　　　早已给他们机会
No, somebody's talking to the Kremlin.
不，有人在跟老尼通话
It says, "America has been the victim of a terrorist attack."
说「美国是恐怖袭击的受害者」
As you can imagine, there has been much confusion here...
你应该想像得到…我方有不少揣测
...and fear.
人心惶惶
But we know the weapon was not Russian.
但我们知道不是俄国动武
"But we know the weapon was not Russian."
「但我们知道不是俄国动武」
What the hell is going on?
怎么回事？
Type exactly what I say.
照我说的打
Who are we talking to?
你究竟是谁？
Ryan. I met you in Moscow with Bill Cabot. He died today in Baltimore.
杰克，我跟局长在莫斯科见过你
- Cut him off. - Launch sequence has begun.
中止通讯　　　已启动核武系统
Two months ago,
两个月前
a neo-fascist named Dressler bought an A-bomb on the black market.
新法西斯主义者斯拿买了原子弹
- Cut him off. - The system can't be cut off.
中止通讯　　　无法中止系统操作
Then get someone to stop him.
那快找人阻止他
- He paid three disaffected Russian... - "scientists to make the bomb active."
他雇用三个俄罗斯…
"He shipped it to the US, where a man named Mason"
然后把它送来美国，一个姓马的
was hired to deliver the bomb and set our countries on a collision course.
是他搞鬼，令我们两国起纷争
This is madness. He is CIA.
胡说八道，他是中情局
We cannot hang our fate on the word of their spy.
我们绝不能听信他们的间谍
What is the harm of listening a bit more?
听多一点没害处吧？
What are you asking of me?
你想我怎么做？
Back down.
就此罢手
What guarantee do I have that President Fowler will follow suit?
有什么可保证霍总统也会收手？
None.
没有保证
You see? He is wasting time.
看见吗？他在浪费时间
We must launch now. We have only moments.
我们得出击，时间无多
Sir, I know you had nothing to do with the Baltimore bomb
我知道你跟巴尔的摩的核爆无关
and you know you didn't, but you're still about to launch a nuclear strike.
你也知道，但你还是要攻打我们
- Yes, sir. That's all, Dr Ryan. - This is about fear.
说够了　　　这都是恐惧之故
Fear of your missiles, fear of our subs.
害怕你们的导弹，我们的潜艇
Fear of being weak, of making a mistake,
害怕做弱者，害怕犯错
the fear of the other guy that had us build these bombs in the first place!
害怕对方率先制造这些烂核弹！
It stopped.
没通讯了
They cut him off.
他们中止了他的通讯
They are going to strike.
他们会出击
Prepare the launch orders now.
准备启动核武系统
30 seconds to launch.
30秒后发射
Oh, my God. Mr President?
老天…总统先生？
We will maintain our defensive alert for the moment,
暂时我们会保持在防卫戒备状态
but our offensive forces are withdrawn.
但是已撤退攻击部队
"If you match this, I propose a phased mutual stand down over five hours."
「若你照这样做」
Stop the launch sequence.
关闭核武系统
Lasseter here. Flash override. Stop the sequence!
这是莱上将，马上关闭核武系统
Order the planes to stand down. Take us to DEFCON-3.
撤走战机，进入三级紧急状态
And would somebody ask Mr Ryan if I can use the phone now?
找人问杰克…我可以用电话了吗？
You're still here.
你还在这儿
There is no more fitting memorial for those who perished in this tragedy
没有什么比我们今周所做的
than the steps we've taken this week
更能悼念这次惨剧的受害者
toward a multinational campaign
以求多国通力合作
to root out and eliminate weapons of mass destruction.
大规模销毁破坏力强大的军备
We embarked on this course because we have learned, at too great a cost,
我们有此目标
that if the most powerful weapons ever created are unleashed,
明白到若我们动用最强大的武器
they will be fired not in anger, but in fear.
那不是因为愤恨，而是恐惧之故
Dr Ryan.
雷博士
Mr Grushkov.
古先生
It is... a lovely day.
今天…是个大好日子
Yeah.
对
- I'm sorry, this is... - Dr Muller. How do you do?
抱歉，这是…　　梅医生，幸会
Nice to meet you.
幸会
Why am I not surprised you know her name?
为何我不为此感到意外？
Our friend William thought I was a spy.
我们的朋友比尔以为我是个间谍
Of course, he could never prove it.
当然他无法证实这个
He never told me you were friends.
他从未说过你们是朋友
Maybe he didn't know you well enough.
也许他跟你不太熟
He told me he had a source in Russia.
他说，他有个俄罗斯线人
"To keep the back channels open?"
「打开秘密渠道」？
"In hopes of staving off disaster."
「以免灾难发生」
Kennedy said, "Our most basic common link"
甘尼迪说过，我们最大的共通之处…
"is that we all inhabit this small planet."
就是同居住于这地球上
"We all breathe the same air."
呼吸相同的空气
"We all cherish our children's future..."
大家都重视儿女的将来
"...and we're all mortal."
还有我们生有尽时
I will miss... so very much talking to William.
我会好怀念…跟比尔合作的日子
Me too.
我也是
Perhaps from time to time
也许日后有机会
you and I can talk.
我们可以合作
Yeah, I'd like that.
乐意之至
What is this?
这是什么？
A modest gift for your engagement.
庆祝你们订婚的小礼物
He... he just asked me this morning.
他…今早才向我求婚
We haven't told anybody about it.
我们还没告诉任何人
How... how could you possibly know?
你怎么可能知道？